like said welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
well we open up with the Ten
Commandments that God commanded the
world to keep brother James yes sir and
God spake all these words saying I'm the
Lord thy God which have brought thee out
of the land of Egypt out of the house of
bondage thou shal H know the gods before
me Thou shalt not make unto thee any
Graven image or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above or that is in
the earth beneath or that is in the
water under the Earth Thou shalt not bow
down thyself to them nor serve them for
I the Lord thy God am a jealous God
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me
and showing Mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my Commandments
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain for the Lord will not
hold him Guiltless that taketh his name
in vain remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy six days shalt thou labor and do
all thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God in it Thou
shalt not do any work thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter thy man's servant nor
thy maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates for in
six days the Lord made Heaven and Earth
the sea and all that in them is and
rested the seventh day wherefore the
Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hollowed it honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee Thou shalt not kill Thou shalt not
commit adultery Thou shalt not steal
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house thou shal not
covet thy neighbor's wife nor is man
servant nor his maid servant nor his Ox
nor his ass nor anything that is thy
neighbors I read Exodus 20:
1-17 may the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of his word in Jesus name we
pray amen amen
amen so here on question and you can ask
us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible and if
we cannot find the answer we will seek
further counsel to bring you an answer
at a later time keep in mind that all
vague questions would not be answered
and all long scripture questions would
not be answered for time sake but we may
be able to point you in the direction of
a DVD or CD that you can purchase by
calling the office so please be as
directed as possible with your questions
out of the King James Bible so we can
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible no
other Bibles will be acknowledged on
this program also keep in mind that this
is a live stream and you may begin in
May begin to send in your questions even
questions that pertain to everlasting
life but let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening
we got brother Dre good evening brother
Julius good evening everybody brother
Jerome and peace brother James good
evening
everyone sister Deborah good evening
brother
Sean good evening and we have the guest
caller with us and I'm brother Cornell
sister Debra let us begin with our first
question of the
evening uh yes there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A
so Doc Martin asks when the Bible says a
certain man is talking about is that
talking about an Israelite or just any
man can you please
explain certain man is it any man or is
it an Israelite brother juli is share
some light good evening everyone that
depends upon the subject matter it
depends upon the subject matter uh let's
go to uh we're talking about a certain
man let's go to our first example First
Kings chapter 22 brother
James First Kings Kings chapter
22 2 just because it says a certain man
does not mean that is always an
Israelite this first Kings 22 and this
was in the days of Jehoshaphat and Ahab
and they were uh at War Israel was at
war with the syrians the syrians were
hites I'm sorry they were
Arabs let's go begin reading at verse 31
look what this king of Syria
said but the king of Syria Comm
commanded his 30 and two captains that
had ruled over CH over his chariots
saying fight neither with small nor
great save only with the king of Israel
now skip down to verse 34 look at look
how it starts go ahead and a certain man
drew a bow at a venture and smok the
King of Israel between the joints of the
harness wherefore he said unto the
driver of his Chariot turn thy hand and
Carry Me Out of the host for I am
wounded now this certain man was a
Syrian Soldier a non-israelite let's go
to acts the 10th chapter quickly Acts
chapter 10 that's why we say you can't
just say a certain man is the Israelite
you have to read the context of the
subject matter acts 10 and just verse
one James go ahead there was a certain
man in Cera called Cornelius a centurion
of the band called The Italian band but
it started out a certain man uh named
Cornelius a centurion so he was a Roman
soldier a gentile and an Italian at that
so this was not an Israelite let's go to
acts the 15th chapter our last place
acts 15 and pick that up at verse one
now let's show you some Israelites who
were Jews go ahead
and a certain man which came down
from started again and certain men which
came down from Judea taught the Brethren
and said except ye be circumcised after
the manner of Moses ye cannot be saved
but it says certain men but these right
here were Israelites that's why you have
to read the context of the subject
matter I hope that
help all right thank you for that
brother I hope that answered today
question as we move on to our next
question yes moving on prayer warriors
says I work in a dental office as a
provider touching many different
patients of different backgrounds and
religions does that make me unclean
touching these patients that might be
eating unclean food before their
appointments yeah uh let's open this up
to the panel because um that's the case
then you won't be able to touch anybody
that's clean at times open to the
pan no don't make you unclean go to
Leviticus the 5th chapter and read verse
two Leviticus 5 verse
two or if a soul touch any unclean thing
whether it be a carcass or an unclean
Beast or a carcass of unclean cattle or
the carcass of unclean creeping thing
and if it be hidden from him he also
shall be unclean and
guilty so it didn't say if a soul touch
a soul that have touched something
unclean it say that a soul touch it so
no you're not unclean long as you didn't
touch no unclean thing it's not talking
about
people don't have to say all right hope
that answers your question as we
continue to move on to our next question
yes Doc Martin says someone asked a
question last week about will there be
human families on Earth you said some of
us will have
families uh when Jesus is on Earth are
these families Immortals or still human
beings that have not been changed
yet all right brother Jerome can you
share some light on that question
question yeah the the some of us that's
going to have families um are going to
be Flesh and Blood because they didn't
make the first
resurrection when the Lord came at the
blowing of the seven trumpet and those
are the ones that are still be human
because they didn't make the first
resurrection uh they were left they
won't be uh
Immortals but uh a thousand years and
the Lord's after the Lord Kingdom A
Thousand
Years uh man going to have to be changed
into uh Immortals because Flesh and
Blood can't live
forever so you know at that time after
the L at the Judgment Day death going to
be cast into the Lake of Fire so it
ain't goingon to be no more dying that
mean can't be no Flesh and Blood because
Flesh and Blood can't live forever so at
that point yeah but uh in the Lord's
Kingdom you going to have a first
resurrection and those that don't make
the first
resurrection they going to remain human
they not going to be Immortals and those
will be the ones that can have children
and families you know I got some verses
but we got a lot to cover today so we we
can
continue right that's all I got
on hope that answered your question as
we continue to move on to our next
question continuing on sister tinisha
asked for you to explain 2 Kings 2 verse
11 2 Kings 2 and verse 11 Why Don't We
Go There Brother James this this um
smells a little bit of someone saying
about someone going to heaven so let's
um let's go there and prepare to read
that 2 Kings
2:11 yes we're going to pick it up
because the first thing that we want
them to understand is that there there's
three Heavens there's the third heaven
where the father and the sun sit and
dwell which no man has ever went to
there's the second heaven which is
outter space and all the way down to the
Earth and then the Earth itself is the
first heaven so let's go to um let's go
and read that let's read that uh Second
Kings and let's pick it up let's read
that verse uh one first so we can show
where it was that Elijah actually went
and it was not the third heaven he just
went up into the second heaven but read
that second Kings 2 read that verse one
for me and it came to pass when the Lord
would take up Elijah into Heaven by a
whirlwind that Elijah went with Elisha
from Gil gout all right so this is not
going to the third this is the Lord
taking Elijah up to the second heaven
which we just spoke about and we're
going to read a little bit more about
that pick it up at verse um n so we can
get right down to it go ahead and it
came to pass when they were gone over
that Elijah said unto Alisha ask what I
shall do for thee before I be taken away
from thee and Alisha said I pray thee
let a double portion of thy Spirit be
upon me and he said thou has asked a
hard thing nevertheless if thou see me
when I am taken from thee it shall be so
unto thee but if not it shall not be so
this is when El Elijah was passing the
mantle on to elishia here who would be
taken over and he was taken up verse 11
go ahead and it came to pass as they
still went on and talked that behold
there appeared a chariot of Fire
and Horses of fire and parted them both
aund and Elijah went up by Whirlwind
into heaven and Elijah went up by
Whirlwind into heaven this is the second
heaven he just went up in the air that's
all but he did not go into the third
heaven where the Father and Son dwell at
so let's go into uh that John 3 John
3 and we're going to read one verse here
John 3
and pick it up at that verse
13 John 3
and13 yes because this will cover that
Elijah did not go up to the third heaven
only to the second heaven where the
birds fly around and and Etc read that
verse 13 for me and no man has ascended
up to heaven but he that came down from
heaven even the son of man which is in
heaven so no man have ascended up but
only he that came down which was Jesus
who came to die for the sins of the
whole world he's the only one that came
down and the only one that went back up
no other man has done that go to uh that
second Kings for me the second chapter
because we're going to show that Elijah
appeared
again okay Second Kings
2 yes Second Kings the second
chapter and when you got when you get
there pick it up and then verse 19 for
me and the men of the city said unto
Alisha behold I pray thee the situation
of this city is pleasant as my Lord
seeth but the water is not and the
ground
bearing and he said all right pull that
right there brother okay hold that right
there all right I want to go to that 2
Chronicles 2 Chronicles the 21st chapter
2 Chronicles
2 2 Chronicles 21 yes sir okay which
verse pick it up at that verse
uh read that verse 12 verse 12 second
chronicles
21 and read verse 12 this is Elijah here
after he was taken up into heaven he
appeared again on the earth go ahead
which is the first Heaven go ahead and
there came a writing to him from Elijah
the prophet saying thus sayeth the Lord
God of David thy father because thou has
not walked in the ways of Jehoshaphat
thy father nor in the ways of Asa king
of Judah but has you stop there brother
I just wanted to show that Elijah was
taken up from alitia went up into heaven
which is in the air and appeared
somewhere else the Lord just took him to
another place he appeared someone
somewhere else and he sent a letter A
Written Letter so it was not the third
heaven it was just merely the second
heaven and then he came back to Earth
and wrote a letter which is the first
heaven and that's all I got for time
sake all right hope that answered your
question we gonna keep it moving
sister yes most love wants you to
explain Isaiah 57 1 and 2 how can one be
walking in his
uprightness when he's resting in
death all right brother Dre what you
say let's go to that Isaiah 57 and we
gonna read verses one and
two brother James get it go
ahead the righteous perish and no man
layeth to heart and the merciful men are
taken away none considering that the
righteous is taken away from the evil to
come he shall enter into peace they
shall rest in their beds each one
walking in his
uprightness now it said in verse one
that the righteous
perish so they
perish they go and rest in peace they
shall rest in their beds that's what it
says there now let's go to ecclesiastics
9 ecclesiastics
9 okay Ecclesiastes 9 okay pick it up
verse
five Ecclesiastes 9 and verse 5 sir for
The Living For The Living know that they
shall die but the dead know not anything
neither have they any more reward for
the memory of them is
forgot read verse six go ahead also
their love and their hatred and their
Envy is now perished neither have they
they anymore a portion forever in
anything that is done under the sun they
don't have any feelings that they going
to have they don't have no Envy no
hatred no love that perish verse 10 go
ahead brother whatsoever thy hand
findest to do do it with thy might for
there is no work nor device nor
knowledge nor wisdom in the grave
whether thou goest that is right so
ain't no you know you you walk around
when you go to the Grave there is none
of that let's go to one last place let's
go to Daniel the 12th chapter Daniel
12 okay Daniel 12 and pick it up read
verse one and uh read verse two verse
two and we gonna skip Daniel 12 and
verse
Two started one I'm sorry go
ahead and at that time shall Michael
stand up the great Prince which standeth
for the children of thy people and there
shall be a time of trouble such as never
was since there was a nation even to
that same time and at that time thy
people shall be delivered everyone that
shall be found written in the book oh
yeah and and many of them that sleep in
the dust of the Earth shall awake some
to everlasting life and some to shame
and everlasting contempt here many
that's going to rise up during this time
they G to raise up out of the
Grave let's look at what Daniel was told
here in verse uh 13 read verse
13 but go thou thy way to the end be for
there's for Thou shalt rest and stand in
thy lot at the end of the days so go thy
Way Daniel you going to rest in the
grave and you will stand in your lot at
the end of the days because that's when
you will be raised up and not a day
before okay that's it yes sir brother
Dre it's GNA be a wonderful time for
Daniel and that's what is a blessing all
right hope that answered your question
as we move on to our next one moving on
Jeffrey
says in Leviticus
23: 23 and 24 is this a Sabbath and no
kindling of Fire please
explain all right Jerome with the
kindling of fire share some
light let's go read it uh Leviticus 23
verse 23 and 24 you get it go ahead and
read and the Lord spake unto Moses
saying Speak unto the children of Israel
saying in the seventh month in the first
day of the month shall ye have a Sabbath
a memorial blowing of trumpets a holy
convocation
read ye shall do no surval work therein
but you shall offer an offering made by
fire unto the Lord and that's all it
said it said don't do no surviv work on
this holy day memorial blowing of the
trumpets but if it happen to fall on a
weekly Sabbath then you shouldn't Kindle
any fire but if it fall on any other day
you know that's not a a weekly Sabbath
then you it didn't say you couldn't k a
fight okay it just said don't do no surv
our work and that means you go on your
job you know and things things of that
nature that that's all I got on all
right thank you for that brother we're
going to keep it moving right along
sister yes Malicia C says in Joshua 10
verse3 and also 2 Samuel 1 verse 18 it
mentions things written in the book of
jasher there is no book of jasher in the
KJV so what are those scriptures talking
about all right they first mentioned
that Joshua 10 and verse 13 let's go
there brother James and that's 2 Samuel
1:18 and the guest caller will take it
from
there okay Joshua 10
verse3 and the sun Stood Still and the
moon stayed until the people had Avenged
themselves upon their enemies is it not
this written in the book of jasher so
the sun Stood Still in the midst of
heaven and hasted not to go down about a
whole
day go
ahead and there was no day like that
before it or after it that the Lord
hearkened unto the voice of a man for
the Lord fought for
Israel now go to 2 Samuel read 1
and8 2 Samuel 1
and18 also he B them he B them teach the
children of Judah the use of the bow
behold it is written in the book of
jasher now the whole thing is is obvious
there's the book of
jasha but the ones that they call the
book of jasha who can
authenticate anybody could have wrote a
book and gave it the name gave it the
name the book of
jasha but book of J is not the one you
should be worried about you should be
worried about this stand King James
Version let's go into uh Revelation the
20th
chapter okay
Revelation Revelation
20 and uh start reading at verse and
read at verse
11 Revelation
20:1 and I saw a great okay and I saw a
great white throne and him that sat on
it from whose face the earth and the
heaven fled away and there was found no
place for them and I saw the dead small
and great stand before God and the books
were open and another book was open
which is The Book of Life and the dead
were judged out of those things which
were written in the books according to
their
works so now this book that you have
this King James version that's the one
you going to be judged out of so you
should be more concerned about what's
written in there than a book that you
cannot authenticate that's all I have to
say all right hope that answers your
question as we continue to move on to
our next question moving on uh prayer
warriors says can the panel please shed
light on the existence of dinosaurs and
is there any scriptures that can help
support that all right talking about the
existence of the dinosaurs brother Julie
is um can you share some light on this
question yes absolutely we know that
dinosaurs existed because we have the
apostles let's go to Genesis the first
chapter Genesis the first chapter but
that was the creation that was not man
that was before man's
creation James Genesis 1 and one one and
and read down to verse
two in the beginning God created the
Heaven and the Earth the book don't give
a date whenever it was it was go ahead
and the Earth was without form and void
and darkness was upon the face of the
deep and the spirit of God moved upon
the face of the waters so now this was
so the Earth was under the water you
read the whole chapter you'll find out
that the Lord said let the dry land
appear so he brought that out the water
so now continue uh to down 27 and 28 go
ahead now he's creating man the first
man Adam go it's telling you how he
going to do it go ahead so God created
man in his own image in the image of God
created he him male and female created
he them and God so man is created man is
created this is after that first flood
now let's go to the ninth chapter of
Genesis man got Wicked the Lord drowned
everybody except Noah and his family and
remember remember what the key word is
uh multiply be fruitful and replenish
the Earth that's what he commanded to
let's see what he told Noah to do verse
one only only verse one go ahead and God
blessed Noah and his sons and said unto
them be fruitful and multiply and
replenish the Earth but that's the same
thing that he told Adam the same thing
that he told Adam let's go to Second
Peter the thir chapter this is my last
place second Peter chapter
3 no yeah dinosaurs existed that's where
we get all our fossil fues from dead
trees plants and uh animal and human uh
bones three and pick it up at verse uh
what I want here pick it up at verse
five go five to seven go ahead for this
they willingly are ignorant of that by
the ignorant willingly mean they don't
care to know but the Lord got this here
for a reason go ahead that by the word
of God the heavens were of old and the
Earth standing out of the water and in
the water whereby the world that then
was being overflow with water perished
but the
heavens go ahead finish it up but the
heavens and the Earth which are now by
the same word are kept in store reserved
unto fire against the day of judgment
and predition of ungodly men so we have
the evidence of dinosaur bones what do
you think we get all this oil all this
natural gas from fossil fuels all the
coal from Plants that's forever how long
many a millennia it it's just the same
thing that's in the earth is in us we
cook with oil we have zinc copper iron
in us so the same thing that the
dinosaurs ate is still in us and we all
have gas not trying to be graphy but the
bottom line is all this stuff come from
flesh and plants so yes dinosaurs
actually existed they actually that's
why but that was not for man creation
that's why you don't see no T-Rexes no
no uh brosaurus no pterodactyls because
that was not for man's creation that was
before man to prep the Earth for man
that's where you get all these natural
resources from Sister Brothers I hope
that
helped right thank you for that brother
appreciate that sister Deborah next
question next question Zion says it is
said that no man has heard God's voice
or seeing his shape so was Adam and Eve
the only two people that actually heard
God's voice and seen
him all right not only is it said it is
is written brother Dre what you say yes
sir it is written let's go to John the
5th chapter and we're going to read
verse
37 verse 37 and we're GNA skip from
there go ahead brother John 5 verse 37
and the father himself which has sent me
have borne witness of me ye have neither
heard his voice at any time nor seen his
image that's right so you never seen the
father's shape at any time but you and
are heard his voice but you heard the
son's voice now skip down to verse
39 search the scriptures for in them ye
think ye have eternal life and they are
they which testify of me that's right so
them scriptures that is talking about
God is talking about Jesus in them
scriptures but let's go to uh John the 1
chapter and we're going to read verse 18
in Exodus 24 it lets you know that Moses
naab AB Who and sevene the elders saw
the god of Israel and they ate with him
now this God that they seen First
Corinthians 101 and4 will let you know
that that was Christ that
followed yes sea so you got to read that
1 Corinthians 10 1-4 on your own but
this no man seeing God let's see who
that is that they didn't see Verse 18 go
ahead brother John the first 18 no man
has seen God at any time the only
begotten son which is in the bosom of
the father he had declared him so the
the son declared the father but no man
have seen the father at any time the god
that they always dealt with that you
think you have eternal life they those
are testifying of Jesus Christ so that's
all I got on
that why don't you read John
537 yes
sir John
537 and the father himself which has
sent me ha borne witness of me ye have
neither heard his voice at any time nor
seen his shape that's right and and that
is read
first was John 5 and 37 and that 39 says
search the scriptures go ahead and read
39th verse search the scriptures for in
them ye think ye have eternal life and
they are they which testify of me that
is right
that's it all right hope that answers
your question as we continue to move on
with the time check yes the time is
804 rodri D Haynes says I have a friend
that thinks that there are floating
Sabbath days he thinks that the Sabbath
day start with new moons what scriptures
can I show
him all right ask the guest call and
share some light on these floating
Sabbath
days okay let's go to Genesis the 1
chapter read verses
14-9 Genesis 1 vers
14 through
19 and God said let there be lights in
the firmament of Heaven to divide the
day from the night and let them be for
signs and for seasons and for days and
years and let them be for lights in the
firmament of the heaven to give light
upon the Earth and it was so and God
made two great lights the greater light
to Rule the Day and the Lesser night
lesser light to rule the night and he
made the Stars also and God set them in
the firmament of Heaven to give light
upon the Earth and to rule over the day
and over the night and to divide the
light from the darkness and God saw that
it was good and the evening and the
morning were the fourth
day so now when the Lord created the
moon and stars and the Sun so he created
the moon on the fourth
day so now how did he get to the fourth
day if the month
starts if the week if if the
uh if the the week starts with the
month should have had a month in order
for you to have a first day of the month
for you to have a first day of the week
according to what your friend said but
this created on the fourth day the moon
was now if that's the case
then that should have the next day uh uh
uh should have
been the first day of the month because
now you got a brand new m Moon that's
can't be newer than that from the day it
was created so then that's when you you
started with the new moon now the next
day should have been the first day but
let's see what day it was read 20 to
23 and God said let the waters bring
forth abundantly the moving creature
that hath light and fou that may fly
above the Earth in the open firmament of
heaven and God created great Wells and
every living creature that moveth which
the waters brought forth abundantly
after their kind and every wing fou
after his kind and God saw that it was
good and God blessed them saying be
fruitful and M and fill the waters in
the seas and let foul multiply in the
earth and the evening and the morning
were the fifth day so
now every time you have a new
Moon you supposed to have the beginning
of a new week if that's the case then
there's an error here in the
Scripture it should have said in the
evening and the morning was the first
day instead of the fifth
day so the moon was created on the day
the day was not created on the moon the
day was around before the moon and when
the moon show up it is the first of the
Moon that it's the first day of the new
moon but it's not the first day of the
week otherwise we this scripture should
have said after the moon was
created it should have said the next day
was the first day instead of the fifth
day that's all I have to say all right
so we hope that brought some clarity for
you dealing with the floating Sabbath
days all right sister let us move on
moving on little mama hay says can you
please say explain John 5 verse 43 is
the father's name Jesus or did he mean
he represents the
father good question Dre what you
say yeah the father's name is and he
father's name so let's read that John 5
and
43 5 and 4 go ahead John 5 and 43 I am
come in my father's name and you receive
me not if another shall come in his own
name him ye will receive so he declared
the the words that the father gave him
let's go to John
17 John
17 okay John 17 G pick it up at verse
four verse four I I have glorified thee
on the earth I have finished the work
which thou gavest me to
do and now oh Father glorify thou me
with thy own self with the glory which I
had with thee before the world was it's
right because he had a glory before the
world was and that Glory was God With
God go ahead I have manifested thy name
unto the men which thou gavest me out of
the world thine they were and thou
gavest them me and they have kept Thy
word dip down to verse
eight for I have given unto them The
Words which thou gavest me and they have
received them and have known surely that
I came out of thee and they have
believed that thou didst send me that's
right so skip down to verse 26 and then
we got one other place go ahead and I
have declared unto them thy name and
will declare it that the love wherewith
thou has loved me may be in them and I
in them that's right he came in the
father's name now let's go to
Philippians the second chapter
Philippians 2 and we gonna pick it up at
verse
five okay Philippians 2 and verse 5 let
this mind be in you which was also in
Christ Jesus
who being in the form of God thought it
not robbery to be equal with God yeah
but made himself of no reputation and
took upon him the form of a servant and
was made in the likeness of
men and being found in fashion as a man
he humbled himself and became obedient
unto death even the death of the
cross Jesus was in the form of God and
and he thought it not robbery to be
equal with God but he made himself of no
reputation and he humbled himself and
became obedient coming in the flesh and
dying on the cross verse nine go ahead
wherefore God also hath highly exalted
him and given him a name which is above
every name that at the name of Jesus
every knee should bow of things in
heaven and things in Earth and things
under the Earth and
that and and that every tongue should
confess that Jesus Christ is Lord to the
glory of God the father that's right
Jesus was given a name which is above
every name father is a title the name
Jesus is the name that was given when
you
baptize you they say baptize in the name
of the father son and the Holy Spirit
you baptized in the name of Jesus you
took care of the business father is a
title I hope that
helps all right brother thank you I hope
that answered they question next
question next question Neo Geo asked for
explanation to John 20 vers 22 and 23
John
2022-23 and they like to have an
explanation let's go there brother James
when you get there read it and the guest
caller will take it from there John 20
and veres 22 and 23 and when he had said
this he breathed on them and said unto
them receive ye the Holy Ghost whosoever
sins ye remit they are remitted unto
them and whosoever sins ye retain they
are
retained okay first we going to deal
with verse 22 when see who breathe on he
breathe on them and they receive the
Holy Ghost that's that's a metaphor I'm
going to give you a good example let's
go to St John the 7th
chapter and read
37 and
38 okay St John 7 and: 37 and
38 and the last day
that great day of the feast Jesus stood
and cried saying if any man thirst let
him come unto me and drink he that
believeth on me as the scripture has
said out of his belly shall flow rivers
of Living
Water now is the rivers of water going
to flow out of Jesus
belly now let's talk about the word go
to Ephesians the 5th chapter and read
verse 26
Ephesians was that 4
and Ephesians 5 and 26 okay Ephesians 5
and
26 that he might sanctify and cleanse it
with the washing of the Water by the
word so now that water that's going come
out of his belly is the word it's all
that simple that's what cleans you the
word of God and nothing else now go to
St John the 6th chapter read verse 51
and
52 St John 651 and 52 I am the living
bread which came down from heaven If any
man eat of this bread he shall live
forever and the bread that I will give
is my flesh which I will give for the
life of the world the Jews the Jews
therefore strove among themselves saying
how can this man give us his flesh to
eat then Jesus said oh I'm sorry did you
finish 52 yes
sir how this man give this flesh to eat
get down to verse 63 and read
it it is the spirit that quickeneth the
flesh profiteth nothing the words that I
speak unto you they are Spirit spirit
and they are life so he wasn't telling
people to fight off his arm and eat his
flesh he was telling them to eat his
word and that's the soall the spirit at
Quicken the flesh profited nothing the
word that I speak they are spirit and
their life skip down and read verse
66-68 from that time many of his
disciples went back and walked no more
with him then said Jesus unto the 12
will ye also go away then Simon Peter
answered himl to whom shall we go thou
Hast the words of eternal
life so that eating his flesh was a
metaphor just like uh uh just like uh uh
uh uh living water coming out of his
mouth was a letter metaphor both of them
represent words and so when you say you
going he breathe on them you have to bre
read the talk that's all he's saying he
taught them nothing more now we're going
to deal with verse 23 now John 2023 and
I read it
again whosoever sins ye remit they are
remitted unto them and whosoever sins ye
retain they are
retained go to Matthew 16 and read verse
19 Matthew
16 verse 19
16 and
19 is and I will give unto thee the Keys
of the Kingdom of Heaven and whatsoever
Thou shalt bind on Earth shall be bound
in heaven and whatsoever Thou shalt
loose on Earth shall be loosed in
heaven so what he going to do then he
going to give him the keys let's see
what these keys are let's go into
Revelation the first chapter and read
Verse 18
Revelation 1 and verse
18 I am he that liveth and was dead and
behold I am alive forever more amen and
have the keys of hell and of
death and so the hell and death let me
see what these Keys is let's go to
Deuteronomy the 30th
chapter Deuteronomy
30 and we going to read verse 8 then
we're going to skip down
30 in verse 8 and thou shalt return and
obey the voice of the Lord and do all
his Commandments which I command thee
this
day and Skip down to verse 11 and read
the verse
14 okay verse 11 for this commandment
which I command thee this day it is not
hidden from thee neither is it far off
it is not in heaven that thou should us
say who shall go up for us to heaven and
bring it unto us that we may hear it and
do it neither is it beyond the sea that
thou should us say who shall go over the
sea for us and bring it unto us that we
may hear it and do it but the word is
very nigh unto thee in thy mouth and in
thy heart that thou mayest do
it see I verse 15 see I have set before
thee this day life in good and death and
evil and that I command and in that I
command thee this day to love the Lord
thy God to walk in his ways to keep his
Commandments and his statutes and his
judgments that thou mayest live and
multiply and the Lord thy God shall
bless thee in the land which thou goest
to possess
it so now he said I set before you
blessing and evil uh blessing and evil
life and death choose life and live so
what did he set before him he set before
him his word and his
commandments so now he to the kingdom is
the word of
God and the uh uh uh uh the uh uh and
whatever whatever Peter them teach the
Lord told Peter three times feed my
people feed him what feed him the word
of God so whatever not so much as Peter
them don't have the power to block
anybody from heaven or block anybody
from the kingdom or put anybody in the
kingdom it is the word like Jesus told a
young man in uh Matthew the 19th Chapter
he said good Master what should I do to
get eternal life he said why ca thou be
good only God is good but if you would
enter into life keep the
Commandments through the keys of heaven
is the word of God that's all I have to
say all right thank you for that hope
that ansed your question as we move on
to our next question moving on ler
says Jesus told a man to pick up his mat
on the Sabbath that's John 5: 8 and N
was he breaking the Sabbath law as
stated in Jeremiah
17 ver 21 and
22 how should I understand
this all right these are two different
situations here if the guy picking up
his mat was polluting the Sabbath day
then we're blaming Jesus for telling him
to pollute the Sabbath day let's go and
read that CU Jesus is the one that told
him to pick up his mat let's let's go to
that John 5 that John the 5th
chapter okay John 5 verse 8-9 well I
want you to read verse read verse five
and six for me first and then we'll skip
down and I just want the person that ask
this question to see the condition of
this guy and what Jesus said unto him
read verse five and six for me and a
certain man was there which had an
infirmity 3 and8 years
for 38 years that's a long time ain't it
Jam yes sir go ahead when when Jesus saw
him lie and knew that he had been now a
long time in that case he saith unto him
will thou be made whole keep read the
impotent man answered him sir I have no
man when the water is troubled to put me
into the pool but while I am coming
another step down before for me so this
pool was designed to heal people first
one to get down first person to get in
that pool was healed or whatever his
Affliction was and because this guy
couldn't walk he was trying to get down
there but somebody always beat him to
the
punch go ahead read Jesus said unto him
rise take up thy bed and walk oh so
after Jesus healed him then he then
Jesus told him to take up thy bed so in
this question when you say when picked
up his mat was he polluting the Sabbath
day no Jesus told him to pick up his bed
and walk verse nine and immediately the
man was made whole and took up his bed
and walked and on the same day was the
Sabbath all right so no he wasn't
polluting the Sabbath day Jesus told him
to pick up his bed and to walk and after
38 years hey I'm sure that guy was full
of joy right Jam
yes sir let's go to that uh the second
one they had was Jeremiah 17 let's go
there because this is dealing with a
person and they weren't and an
individual and what you should and
should not be doing on the Lord's holy
Sabbath day because he did tell us that
that day is Holy and it is Honorable and
it is a day of the Lord so let's go and
read that because we supposed to call
this day a delight
holy of the Lord honorable and we
supposed to honor him not doing our own
ways nor speaking our own words Jeremiah
17 when you get there brother pick it up
at that verse 21 for me okay thus sayeth
the Lord take heed to yourselves and
bear no burden on the Sabbath day nor
bring it into thy and by thy Gates of
Jerusalem so this is not dealing with a
mat or a bed here this is dealing with
how the Lord want us to act as
individuals on his Sabbath day go ahead
neither carry forth a burden out of your
houses on the Sabbath day day neither do
ye any work but hallow ye the Sabbath
day as I commanded your fathers and the
Lord saying he don't want you to do no
work and he wants you to hollow that day
respect that day and he don't want you
to even carry forth a burden when you
come to the house of the Lord you should
have some joy in your heart verse
23 but they obeyed not neither inclined
their ear but made their next step that
they might not hear nor receive
instruction so they GNA do it the way
they want to do it and pollute the
Lord's Sabbath day read
24 and it shall come to pass if ye
diligently hearken unto me sayeth the
Lord to bring in no burden through the
gates of this city on the Sabbath day
but Hollow the Sabbath day to do no work
therein that the Lord was going to bless
you just like he said in Isaiah 58 that
if you do it according to what he say
and how he say do it now let's go into
Nehemiah and see some of these burdens
that they was bearing on the Sabbath day
you got 2 Chronicles Ezra and then you
got Nehemiah just let's just read a
couple of scriptures of what they was
doing back here in nehemiah's time
Nehemiah 13
and when you get there brother pick it
up at that verse 14 because Nehemiah was
trying to straighten up the way things
should be for God and he wanted it to be
remembered for good for him go ahead
Nehemiah 13 ver14 remember me oh my God
concerning this and wipe not out my good
deeds that I have done for the house of
my God and for the offices thereof now
here they go bearing a burden James read
it
in those days saw I in Judah some
treading wine presses on the Sabbath day
and bringing in sheep and lading asses
as also wine grapes and figs and all
manner of burdens which they brought
into Jerusalem on the Sabbath day and I
testified against them in the day were
in they sold victuals and they out there
selling groceries and all if they doing
all this brother James where is the
Sabbath day exactly it don't even exist
to these people read one more verse for
me there dwelt men in tyr also therein
which brought fish and all manner of
wear and sold on the Sabbath day unto
the children of Judah in Jerusalem now
they doing all kind of works on the
Lord's Sabbath day it ain't honorable
unto them it ain't holy unto them read
that last verse 17 and this is the bird
go ahead then I contended with the
Nobles of Judah and said unto them what
evil thing is this that ye do and
profane the Sabbath day so all that they
was doing they was profaning the Sabbath
day of the Lord they weren't treating it
like it was honorable and and holy unto
the Lord so this is the burden that they
were bearing in that Jeremiah the 17th
chapter that you inquired about and
that's all I get
that's caller go right
ahead you know
uh Jesus told me to pick up the bed I
want to show you something here let's
see
uh let's start at 12 at 12 and
one is that John on Matthew 12
mhm okay Matthew chap
12 and verse
one okay Matthew 12 and verse one at
that time Jesus went on the Sabbath day
through the corn and his disciples were
in hunger and began to pluck the ears of
corn and to eat but when the Pharisees
saw it they said unto him behold thy
disciples do that which is not lawful to
do upon the Sabbath
day but he said unto them have ye not
read what David did when he was in
hunger and they were they were with him
how he entered into the house of God and
did eat the showbread which was not
lawful for him to eat neither for them
which were with him but only for the
priest so when David them ate the bread
you know they they defile the law but
keep reading or have ye not read in the
law how that on the Sabbath days that
the priests in the temple profane the
Sabbath and are
blameless but I
say how the priest forame the saath and
they are
blameless because the Lord said don't
kle the fire on the Sabbath day but the
Lord also said you have to make the
evening and the morning comption that
mean you have to do sacrifices every day
so now Jesus Through Being at Jesus told
this man to pick up his bed then that
gave him power to do it just like the
priest had to do sacrifice sure they
profane the Sabbath and the man did it
when he picked up the bed but when God
tell you to do he is the one that gave
you the Sabbath day read the next
verse verse six but I say unto you that
in this place is one greater than the
temple
now go ahead but if ye have known what
this
meanthe and not sacrifice ye would not
have condemned the
Guiltless for the for the son of man is
Lord even on the of the Sabbath day so
Jesus God yes and what he tell you to do
you do it no matter what day it is
but you ain't supposed to profane the
Sabbath day but there are instances when
things happen this man was sick so he
healed him but Jesus healed
it and also uh the priest had to make
the animal sacrifice because Jesus
before he became Jesus told him they got
to do this sacrifice for seven days a
week so they still defil the Sabbath day
but they was Guiltless it depends on the
reason that you defile the Sabbath day
that's all I have to say
yeah all right it was good bag up there
and we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next one
moving on uh Valencia says can you tell
me who are these honorable women in Acts
13 verse 50 The Honorable women in Acts
13 brother Julia shed some light a
mixture of Jews and gentiles
acts the 13 let's read that
verse Acts 13-
50 but the Jews stirred up The Devout
and honorable women and the chief men of
the city and raised persecution against
Paul and Barnabas and expelled and
expelled them out of their Coast now
remember that the Jews always causing
trouble with their own people let's back
up and read verse 42 because the Gentile
Paul is running Israel's history just
whole history down just like Stephan did
in Acts the 7th chapter verse and he in
the synagogue but the Gentiles are
outside gleaning verse 42 James go ahead
and read and when the Jews were gone out
of the synagogue the Gentiles besought
that these words might be preached to
them the next Sabbath day so what
happened the next Sabbath day Skip down
to verse
44 and the next Sabbath day came almost
the whole city to together to hear the
word of God and the Jews didn't like
that you could read the whole chapter on
your own now uh Paul is letting them
know that now the gospel and the
preaching of Jesus is now preached among
the Gentiles verse 48 please go
ahead and when the Gentiles heard this
they were glad and glorified the word of
God of the Lord and as many as were
ordained to eternal life believe now go
to the 14th chapter and pick up at verse
one let's look at it again at another
synagogue go ahead and it came to pass
in Iconium that they were both together
in a synagogue of the Jews and so spake
that a great multitude both of the Jews
and also of the Greeks believed so we
got the Jews and the Greeks believe
quickly last place go to the acts the
17th
chapter okay acts 17 Paul is at
Thessalon now thessalonica pick it up at
verse one and then we'll
skip now when they had passed through
anilus and abalonia they came to
thessalonica where was a synagogue of
the Jews skip down to verse
four and some of them believed and
consorted with Paul and Silas and of The
Devout Greeks a great multitude and of
the chief women not a few now verse 11
this our last place 11 and 12 go ahead
these were more noble than those in
thessalonica and that they received the
word with all Readiness of mind and
searched the Scriptures Daily whether
those things were so yeah go ahead
therefore many of them believed and of
also of honorable women which were
Greeks and of men not a few so it was
always a mixture because Israel was SC
during the Roman Empire and everywhere
they were scattered they had a synagogue
there and so when Paul and them got
around to preaching the gospel to the
Gentiles the Gentiles believed and
Israel always kicked and then some
eventually would believe and some would
not but when the Gentile believed it was
a mixed multitude and so that included a
mixed multitude of Jews and Greek women
also that's all I got I hope that
helped that's right brother Julius
whatsoever women want salvation let them
come right brother my house should be
called a house of prayer for all people
all people all right thank you for that
sister Deborah I believe we getting
ready to go into new
territory yes we are now into tonight's
Q&A for Wednesday October the 9th
2024 Kenisha Mia said I was wondering if
I would be in error if I got baptized at
my childhood Church even though they
don't keep the
Commandments I I'm not close to any
iog and can't afford to
travel yes you would be in Era if you go
back to your childhood Church to get
baptized where they do not keep the
Commandments of God you would be an
error let's go Deuteronomy 7 Deuteronomy
7 and let's see what it said here about
the Commandments Deuteronomy the 7th
chapter when you get there brother pick
it up at that verse nine Deuteronomy 7
and N yes know therefore that the Lord
thy God he is God the faithful God which
keepeth Covenant and mercy with them
that love him and keep his Commandments
to a thousand
Generations that's even in this time
sister so you got to hey you can't go to
where they don't keep the Commandments
should be in direct violation of what we
are reading here getting baptized go
ahead brother and repay them that hate
him to their face to destroy them he
will not be slacked to him that hateth
him he will repay him to his face uhhuh
Thou shalt therefore keep the
Commandments and the statutes and the
judgments which I command thee this day
to do them all right so you have to keep
the Commandments because in them are the
pathway to eternal life so you can't go
and get baptized somewhere where they do
not keep the Commandments let's go
quickly to John 14 John the 14th
chapter and I understand what you said
about your situation but you should call
the office also and let's have a
conversation and just see maybe be a
church that you may not know about but
let's um have a conversation John
14 read verse 6 for me what did Jesus
say Jesus saith unto him I am the way
the truth and the life no man cometh
unto the father but by me so Jesus is
the only way he is the way the truth and
the light and he came preaching the
commandments so you can't uh turn back
read verse 15 and we got one more after
that go ahead if ye love me keep my
Commandments if you love the Lord then
you have to keep his Commandments now
let's go into that 2 Corinthians 11
right
quick because you have found something
here very precious the true word of God
and you can't look back and go where the
Commandments are not kept and let's see
where they don't keep the Commandments
what's going on at that place second
Corinthians 11 and2 go ahead for I am
jealous over you with Godly jealousy for
I have espoused you to one husband that
I may present you as a Chase virgin to
Christ so Paul is saying hey he's
jealous and
Heil and also talk about one God go
ahead but I fear least by any means as
the serpent begal Eve through his subti
subtility so your mind should be
corrupted from the Simplicity that is in
Christ but there is no Commandments that
can happen go ahead for if he that
cometh preaches another Jesus whom we
have not preached or if you receive
another Spirit which ye have not
received or another gospel which ye have
not accepted ye might well bear with him
so where they don't teach the
Commandments is another Jesus that's not
the Jesus of Abraham Isaac and Jacob the
god that came to die for the sins of the
world so you have to be
strong and just hold on and pray that
God will
deliver but as far as going back and
getting baptized where they don't even
keep the Commandments that yes you will
be an error
definitely that's all I
get and we hope that that aned your
question there and let us keep moving
sister deor yes David staniel ask can we
cook on blowing of the trumpet day all
right I believe brother Jerome you
expounded on that a little bit earlier
saying it it just mentioned that uh
serve our work right brother can you
pick it up from
there yeah um no s our work but if it
fall on the weekly Sabbath then you
can't CLE the fire and you can't
cook all right thank you for that
brother appreciate it hope that answered
your question as we keep moving yes
Xavier beavers asks how can I be
forgiven for the sin of lust brother Dre
what you say because that sin of lust
how can they be
forgiven uh repenting and not feeding
those lust let's go to uh first John the
2 chapter 1 John
2 start at verse one brother first John
2 verse one go ahead my little children
these things write I unto you you that
ye sin not and if any man sin we have an
advocate with the father Jesus Christ
the
righteous and he is the propitiation for
our sins and not for our sins only but
also for the sins of the whole world
that's right go ahead and hereby we do
know that we know him if we keep his
Commandments all right brother now I
want you to skip down to uh
to verse
15 love not the world neither the things
that are in the world if any man love
the world the love of the father is not
in
him for all that is in the world the
lust of the Flesh and the lust of the
eyes and the pride of life is not of the
father but is of the world Y and the
world passes away and the lust thereof
but he that doeth the will of God
abideth forever and you got to keep this
in mind at every turn you make in life
that lust is there and they are feeding
the lust that may be in you if you
eating it you are what you eat if you
eating garbage you gonna do garbage
things if you eating this word and you
letting that word meditate you
meditating on it day and night as it
says in Psalm 1
then you be like the tree and lust won't
rule over you but you cannot feed lust
and then wonder how how can you be
forgiven for it when that's what you eat
that's the table that you eating
from lust in the end it brings forth sin
and when it is finished it will bring
forth death so don't feed it that's all
I got on
that all right thank you for that
brother hope that answered that question
as we keep moving with the time
check yes the time is
844 rodri Hayes says to my own knowledge
I know it's okay to drink liquor but can
you go in death more or not getting
drunk also is it a sin to smoke
weed all right so they know it's not say
to be drinking but can you go into
getting drunk drunk can definitely be a
violation trying to go overboard let's
open this up to the panel but let's go
to Proverbs 20 right quick brother James
and then open it up to the
panel okay see what it
say Proverbs 20 yes and and just read
that one verse one for
me wine is a mocker strong drink is
Raging and whosoever is deceived thereby
is not wise yeah so you have to know
your limit and you have to know that
getting drunk is not good because
sometimes you go overboard and you start
to get this rage of anger and things of
that nature so you have to know your
limits so that you don't commit sin or
get in trouble with God panel what else
can we give for
that 1 Corinthians
5:1 First Corinth
5 and verse
11 1 Corinthians verse 5 and
11 but now I have written unto you not
to keep Company If any man that is
called a brother be a fornicator or
Covetous or an idolator or or
drunkard or an extortioner with such one
such and one not know not to
eat so now you see the company that
drunkers of a part
of because when you drunk ain't no
telling what you might do so if you're
drunker that mean somebody has continue
to move in that
fashion that's all I have to say on that
but as for the second part of smoking
weed is a is a uh is a sin the question
is but somebody go and and read what sin
is john4
first 3 and
four ver John 3 and4 whosoever committes
sin transgresseth also the law for sin
is the transgression of the
law so smok and re is not is not a sin
sin is the transgression of the law but
if the uh civil Authority say you can't
do it then the Bible tell you also to
obey the laws of the
land right but you
can't yeah cor can we go to Galatians 5
piggy backing off the guest caller
Galatians
5 all right okay pick it up at
19 Galatians 5 and 19 yep now the works
of the flesh are manifest which are
these adultery fornication
uncleanliness
lasciviousness idolatry witchcraft
hatred varience emulations wrath Strife
seditions
hearsays envyings murderers drunkenness
reings rings and such like of that which
I tell you before as I have also told
you in time past that they which do such
things shall not inherit the kingdom of
God that's all I
got that's correct you have uh you have
a lot of people that got in trouble
being drunk that they would never have
did if they didn't go too far all right
hope that answered your question next
question sister as time is a ticking
when you having fun yeah yes Justin P
asks does Deuteronomy 7 verse3 and 4
state
intermingling is forbidden solely due to
the
possibility of the strangers influence
on Israel with idolatry or that it is
forbidden flat out Deuteronomy 73 and 4
about to ENT mingling go there and read
it brother James guest caller we take it
from there Deuteronomy 7:3 and 4 neither
shalt thou make marriages with them thy
daughter Thou shalt not give unto his
son nor his daughter shalt thou take
unto thy son for they will turn away thy
son from following me that they may
serve other gods so will the anger of
the Lord be kindled against you and
Destroy thee
suddenly so the whole thing is he said
don't do it don't marry because they
will turn you away from your God mhm but
then what if you're strong let's give
you an example let's go into numbers the
12th chapter read
1-5 9 and
10 numbers 12 1-5 and 9 and
10 and Miriam and Aaron spake against
Moses because of the Ethiopian woman who
he had married for he had married an
Ethiopian woman and they said had the
Lord indeed spoken only by Moses Moes
had he not spoken also by us and the
Lord heard it now the man Moses was very
Meek above all the men which were upon
the face of the earth and the Lord spake
suddenly unto Moses and unto Aaron and
unto Miriam come out ye three unto the
Tabernacle of the congregation and they
three came out and the Lord came down in
the pillar of the cloud and stood in the
door of the Tabernacle and called Aaron
and Miriam and they both
came verse 9 and the anger of the Lord
was kindled against them and he departed
and the cloud departed from off the
Tabernacle and behold Miriam became
leprous white as snow and Aaron looked
upon Miriam and behold she was leprous
and Aaron said unto Moses alas my Lord I
beseech thee lay not the sin Upon Us
wherein we have done foolishly wherein
we have
sinned see what they did was they called
Moses out and the law said don't marry
no other people but if we had read on
that it would have told you that uh that
the Lord said Moses a proven servant to
me yes so if you can marry somebody and
you outside of
Israel then a lot of time they'll turn
you away CU I have a good example I knew
a brother that was in the class and he
married an
Edomite and she took him clean away from
this word got him doing bom MIT and all
that kind of stuff but
then David's grandmother was a
moabit that was Ruth Ruth said told her
mother-in-law which was Israelites your
God is my God and your land is my land
and your people are my people so it all
depends on the
person if it was an absolute then God
would not have uh uh chur Miriam white
because she spoke against Moses for man
an Ethiopian woman that's all I got to
say all right hope that answered your
question is we keep
moving yes he also
asked uh for you to explain brief
briefly where the scripture link
observance of Memorial of trumpets to
Revelation all right Julius share some
light we just had a uh we just
celebrated memor Memorial blowing the
trumpets you Leviticus the 23rd chapter
uh tells you about the memorial blowing
the tra trumpets and it's all the feast
days uh deal with the
Salvation the salvation and the coming
of Jesus Christ but so on your own you
can go ahead go to your YouTube and get
the lesson on that or get the app iog
app and you can go back and watch that
whole lesson and it dealt walk the
lesson all the way down to uh to the
seven trumpets but I'mma give you this
right here Revelation 11th
chapter cuz the trumpets announc the
coming of a king and announces War
announces a lot of things seven trumpets
got to sign before the Lord come back
Revelation
11 and pick it up at verse 15 because
this is the seventh trumpet and look
what happen when this seventh trumpet
sounds go ahead and the seventh Angels
sounded and there were great voices in
heaven saying the kingdoms of this world
are become the kingdoms of our Lord and
of his Christ and he shall reign forever
and ever that's what we keep the
memorial of the blowing the traffic of
trumpets it reminds us that the trumpets
in every generation the trumpet remind
us of the coming of the Lord at this
seventh trumpet and the falling down of
this Earth just like it was in the days
of Joshua when Joshua and them sounded
the walls of Jericho fell flat and they
went in and took the city but I strongly
exhort you to go back and go to your ID
app or go to your YouTube look up iog
the memorial of blowing the trumpet able
to expain that the seven trumpets to a
that's all I got
Corel all right we're going to keep it
moving sister Deborah's time is running
out yeah uh
AHS when God's chosen people are
gathered in the wilderness would they
physically see Jesus Christ or would it
be like Exodus when they see God's
wonders through some one like Moses
brother
Jerome well when God's um people are
gathered to the Wilderness and I don't
want you to get that mixed up with the
fleeing to the Wilderness when God's
people are gathered to the Wilderness
what they going to
see is the Lord in the cloud and in the
fire that he going to be in okay and he
don't change just like he did it in the
past he going to do it the same way when
he returned okay so let's look at the
past let's go to Deuteronomy chapter 5
verse
1-4 okay Deuteronomy
5 verses
1-4 yeah and Moses called all Israel and
said unto them here o Israel the
statutes and judgments which I speak in
your ears this day that ye may learn
them and keep and do them the Lord Our
God made a covenant with us in horror
the Lord made not this Covenant with our
fathers but with with us even us who are
all of us here alive this day the Lord
talked with you face to face in the
mount out of the midst of the
fire so that face of face don't mean
they literally seeing his face they mean
he right there with them that ain't that
ain't an angel that that's here that's
that's the Lord Lord himself but he in a
cloud in and in fire okay and that's
what they saying and he right there with
him and let's go see him doing that same
thing when he gather his people okay go
to um Ezekiel
20 and read verse
33-35 Ezekiel
20 verses
33-35 as I live sayeth the Lord God
surely with a mighty hand and with a
stretched out arm and with Fury poured
out will I rule over you and I will
bring you out from the people and will
gather you out of the countries wherein
ye are scattered with a mighty hand and
with a stretched out arm and with Fury
poured out and I will bring you into the
Wilderness of the people and there will
I plead with you face to face just like
pleaded with your fathers when I took
them out of Egypt it actually say that
in the next few verses okay that's all I
got on everybody want to
ask right think you hit the nail on the
head brother as we keep moving
sister yes uh ly Marie asks can we use
an electric teapot and a and a air fryer
on the Sabbath or would this be
considered killing the fire
not actually not actually kindling the
fire but you are still polluting the
Sabbath day by using the electric tea
Poots and the air fryers and the
microwaves all of this stuff is not
actually preparing for the Lord's
Sabbath day like he requested that we do
remember this is a holy day of the Lord
and all of this you can do for six days
but on that day the Lord asks that we do
it according to what he say Exodus 16
let's go to Exodus the 16th chapter come
there all right pick it up at verse 11
then we go skip down to
22 Exodus 16 verse 11 and then 22
brother go ahead and the Lord spake unto
Moses saying verse speak yes and it came
to pass that on the sixth day they
gathered twice as much bread two armers
for one man and all the rulers of the
congregation came and told Moses yes and
he said unto them this is that which the
Lord has said tomorrow is the rest of
the holy Sabbath unto the Lord bake that
which ye will bake today and seeth that
which will ye will seee and that which
remaineth over lay up for you to be kept
until the morning so the Lord say that
the Sabbath day is a rest and holy unto
the Lord so if you got some boiling or
some bacon or using want to use your
electric teapot or air fryer or
microwave do it on that Friday before
the Sabbath come in and prepare you
enough to have on the Sabbath day so
that you don't pollute the Lord's
Sabbath day Skip down to verse 28 and go
ahead and the Lord said unto Moses how
long refuse ye to keep my Commandments
and my laws this is when you're doing it
contrary to the Lord go ahead 29 see for
that the Lord ha given you the Sabbath
therefore he giveth you on the sixth day
the bread of two days abide ye every man
in his place let no man go out of his
place on the Seventh Day verse 30 so the
people rested on the seventh day and
that's what the Lord wants you to do
prepare for his Sabbath day and rest on
that day don't do it your way Isaiah 58
let's read that right quick brother
Isaiah
58 Isaiah
58 Lord wants you to make his Sabbath
day about him doing it the way he say do
it go ahead brother verse 13 this is
what you should be doing go ahead if
thou turn away thy foot from the Sabbath
from doing thy pleasure on my holy day
and call the Sabbath a delight light the
holy of the Lord honorable and shall
honor him not doing thine own ways nor
finding thine own pleasure nor speaking
thine own
words then shalt thou Delight thyself in
the Lord and I will cause thee to ride
upon the high places of the earth and
feed thee with the heritage of Jacob thy
father for the mouth of the Lord has
spoken it all right so Lord just said
how he want us to do his Sabbath day and
believe you me if you do it the way the
Lord say do it he will be pleased with
you on that day so put away all those
other things that you can do on the
other six days and respect God's Sabbath
day that's all I
get all right okay uh brother Cornell I
would like to give these two questions
they are pertaining to the atonement and
they can be answered uh fairly
quickly uh the two questions and I'm
going to read both of them iwitness say
so are we not to take medication on this
feast day of atonement and Stephen Gus
asked are women allowed to eat on day of
atonement if they breastfeeding an
infant all right so we're going to open
that up to the Past but if you got
medication to take yeah you can you have
to take your medication some medications
say you have to take it with water and
you even have to put some food on your
stomach sometimes because it can make
you sick so Lord don't want you all sick
on this atonement or in the ER so some
things you have to do in order to be
able to still be a part of the Lord's
atonement open to the panel for some
more
guess caller you got something to add to
that well if you have a condition and
you have to take your medicine you have
to take your medicine even on the day of
atonment because your that's equivalent
to your Ox has fall into well on the sth
day yes that's for the child because you
don't eat eat a whole lot the day
before so if you don't have a medical
condition you should not eat or drink
anything
eat and drink and I'm pretty sure you
your child you can have enough milk to
feed your child for one
day all I have to say all right we gonna
leave it right there sister Deborah and
uh yes go ahead can you inform the
audience about Q&A for this Sunday
coming up please Sunday October the 13th
after you come and take part in D on the
day of atonement at 12: noon after the
lesson is over 30 minutes after that we
will have a question and answer in the
sanctuary at class so we just wanted to
bring you all up to speed on that this
Sunday October the 13 30 minutes after
class we will have a Q&A session then
also so yes and uh it will be on the
phone line if you have a question and uh
on YouTube it will be there also all
right same rules apply that we read
always on our regular Wednesday Q&A we
ask that you keep your questions
streamlined so that we may cover some
ground on that day but we want to thank
everybody who tuned in with us from all
around the world and if you submitted a
question and we didn't have a chance to
get to it don't resubmit because sister
Deborah would take that question put it
in rotation and we will answer that
question next Q&A so until we all come
together again thank you be safe be
blessed and may the Lord have mercy on
us all brother James close us out yes
sir Our Father which art in heaven
Hallowed be thy name thy kingdom come
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our debts as we forgive
our Deb and lead us not into
temptation but Deliver Us from Evil for
thine is the kingdom and the power and
the glory forever in Jesus name we pray
amen amen